A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Cooperative Extension, 1862-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series III. Bob Swain Records, 1907-1990
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1960-1974
    - Budgets
      - Cooperative Extension Budget (with working papers), 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - County Budget Forms, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
      - Fiscal Year 1974 Budget Work Papers, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Commonwealth of Virginia Budget, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Financial Reports and Statements
      - Annual Financial Report, 1965-06-30 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Financial Statement, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Appalachia Area Special Report, 1965-1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Annual Financial Report, 1966-06-30 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Annual Financial Report of the Virginia State Cooperative Extension Service, 1966-06-30 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Annual Financial Report, 1967-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Fiscal Year 1967-1968 Financial Report, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Financial Report, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Federal Financial Report, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Federal Auditors Report, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Financial Report, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Annual Financial Report, 1970-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Annual Financial Report, 1971-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Report on Audit, 1971-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Cooperative Extension Service Financial Report with working papers, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Annual Financial Report, 1972-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Annual Financial Report Cooperative Extension Records, 1973-06-30 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Cooperative Extension Service Report for Fiscal Year (End 6-30-1974), 1974 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Financial Statements (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Allotments
      - Allotment Requests, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Allotment Requests, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Allotment Requests, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Extension Allotments, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Legislative Documents
      - Title VII Senate Bill 3462 Rural Community Assistance Consortium, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Public Law 91-516 Environmental Education Handbook, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Retirement Legislation, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Federal Examiner, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Rural Educational Agencies, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Appropriations and Federal Funds, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Agents' Increases, 1965-09-01 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Extension Donations
      - Extension Service (Nematodes) Pl. Path, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - VPI Educational Foundation - Peanut Blight Plant Pathology, 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Flue-Cured Tobacco Commission, 1957-1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Report on Audit (Fiscal Year Ended 6-30-1961), 1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Salary Adjustments, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Insurance Information, 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Policy Memorandums of Understanding & Agreement State
      - Miscellaneous - Program Areas in Agr., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Commission on the Industry of Agriculture, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Natural Resource Film, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        Scope and Contents
        Memorandum of Agreement between CES, Soil Conservation Soceity of America and the Va. Resource Education Council
      - Consumer & Marketing Service (Tobacco), 1978 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Chart of Accounts, 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Hotel Roanoke and Motor Inn Roanoke, VA - Sales Tax Question on Conference, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Correspondence and Documents, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - The Standard Manual for Supervisors, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Letter of Credit
      - Letter of Credit, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Letter of Credit, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Letter of Credit Federal Extension Service, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Federal Extension Service Letter of Credit, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Civil Service Retirement Box, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Nutritions, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Nutrition Budget Forms, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Month Summary By Fund Within Activity, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Statement of Extension Transactions, 1970-06-30 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Pie Charts Ext. Division, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Travel Regulations, 1970-07-01 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - 1890 College (Va. State), 1970-1977 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - VPI Educational Foundation Extension Account - Nonmetropolitan Planning Conference - Dr. Gene McMurtry, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Expenditure Accounting System Users Guide, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Standard Reference Map and Guide of Virginia, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Accounting Forms, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Federal Extension Letters and Fund Information, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Tazewell County, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Computerized Dairy Feed - Mgt. System Extension Service, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - County Appropriation (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Historical Financial Budgets, Records, and Reports, 1975-1990
    - Letter of Credit
      - Letter of Credit, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Fiscal Year 1976-1977 Letter of Credit Extension Service USDA, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Letter of Credit 1977-1978 Extension Service Va. Cooperative Extension Service, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Allocations
      - Allocations, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Allocations, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Allocations, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence and Allocations, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence and Allocations, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Allocations, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Allocations, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Legislative Documents
      - The Budget Bill, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Supplement to the Budget Bill, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Chapter 685, 1977-04-03 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - The Budget Bill - House Bill No. 30 - Biennium, 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Chapter 760, 1980-04-07-1980-06-13 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - House Bill No. 1250, 1981-01-14 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Budgets
      - ESUSDA Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 25-27)
      - Federal Ext. Service Budget Information, 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
      - Western Region Consortium Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - E.S. USDA Fiscal Year 1975 - VA Cooperative Ext. Annual Budget, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Budget Exhibit, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 5-7)
      - Department of Planning and Budget, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Margaret Groseclose, 1976-07-01 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - An Inventory and Evaluation of Coop Ext. Programs in the South Aimed at Small and Part Time Farmer, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Smyth County, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - E.P.A. Pesticide Applicator Box Training - Mr. Frank Ellmore, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - FY 1978 Pest Management Project Proposal and Budget, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Cooperative Ext. Agreement 12-05-300-408, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Solar Demonstration, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - 4-H Education Center Documents, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Program and Financial Exhibit, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Addendum Exhibit, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Report Audit, 1980-06-30 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Program Exhibit, 1984-1990 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Financial Exhibit, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Addendum Exhibit, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Addendum Exhibit, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Financial Report, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - User's Guide VPI & SU Equipment Inventory System, 1978-07 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Historical Overview of Extension, 1979-04 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Business and Financial Plan, 1981-05-11 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Report on Audit, 1985-06-30 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Correspondence and Documents, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Payroll reimbursements, Budget purposal, extension staff support, group statistics, outreach service consideration
    - Swain - CRD Non-Cooperative Extension, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - VA Cooperative Extension Field Staff Listing and Staff Groups, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Restructuring, 1989-03-15 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - An Analysis of Program Structure for the Extension Division, 1989-04-12 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Suggested Service Organizational Chart, 1990-04-11 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Extension Administration Records, 1994-1997
  - Extension Administration Records [RESTRICTED], 1994-1997
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted due to confidentiality and personally identifiable information.
    - 028-140070, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - 028-140072, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 028-140292, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 028-141068, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - 028-141118, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - 028-141119, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 028-141120, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 028-141121, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 028-141123, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - 028-141128, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - 028-141162, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - 028-141196, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - 028-146815, 1994-1997 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Unnamed File, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - 028-545704, 1994-1996 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - 028-545711, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - 028-545720, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - 028-545721, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - 028-547725, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - 028-545740, 1995-1997 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - 028-545752, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - 028-546891, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - 028-546908, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - 028-547731, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - 028-547732, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - 028-547763, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - 028-548318, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - 028-548381, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - 028-551991, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Computer Charges: 140908, 140936, 140943, 1995-1997 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Field Offices, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Voided SPO's, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Foundation, 1995-1997 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - 465-141008, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Dept. Listings 028, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Dept. Listings 640, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Dept. 464 (Old), 1994-1997 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Dept. 644, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Dept. 028, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - 028-548381, 1994-1996 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - 028-548318, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Unnamed File, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 028 Printouts, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 644 Salary, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Unnamed File, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 464 Revenue, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 640 Salary, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 146815, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 545660, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Salary Accounts, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Revenue Accounts, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Foundation - P.O., 1997 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - VT Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - 028-140070, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Series V. Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1862-1993
  - Action Report
    - JLARC Action Report, 1980-05-01 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - JLARC Action Report, 1980-10-1 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - JLARC Action Report, 1980-12-04 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - JLARC Action Report, 1981-04-03 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - JLARC Status of Action Report, 1983-6-30 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - JLARC Status of Action Report, 1985-06-07 (Box 17, Frame 16)
    - JLARC Status of Action Report, 1987-05-20 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
    - Staff Communication, 1979-09-11 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Misc. Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - News and Media
    - News Articles, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - News Items, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - News Articles, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Press Media, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - News Articles, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - News Articles, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Recordings, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Margie Fisher Telephone Call, 1979-03-23
    - Interview, 1978-08-04
    - Sqamons Interview, 1978-08-04
    - Interview with Reporter from Norfolk, 1978-08-02
    - Unnamed Reel
  - Cooperative Extension: History of Legislation, 1862-1914 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Background Materials Extension Budget Guidelines Task Force Report, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
  - Budget Guidelines Report, 1978-10 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Report to Extension Budget Guidelines Task Force, 1978-10 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Materials Returned by JLARC, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Distribution of Funding, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Extension Budget Guidelines Task Force, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Extension Budget Guidelines Task Force (internal), 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Report to Del. Frank M. Slayton and Background Materials, 1978-1980 (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
  - Frank Slayton Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - CEC Billing Process, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Findings and Recommendations from JLARC, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - In-Service Training Course Evaluation, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - JLARC Report Distribution, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Policy to Avoid Competition, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Program Evaluations, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Program Reporting, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Travel Voucher Review, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - JLARC Exposure Draft and Response, 1979-07-20 1979-08-24 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 1979-09 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - CEC Administrative Overhead, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - College Faculty on Grants, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Distribution of Task Force Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Extension Agent Orientation, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Conflict of Interest, 1979-1983 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - General: JLARC Recommendations, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Interagency Coordinate Committees, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Plans of Work, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Programs Leader Positions, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Publication Listings, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Sep 57, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Statement of Role and Mission, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Statewide Study of Off-Campus Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Tenure of Administrative Faculty Positions, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Travel Voucher Post-Audit, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - CEC Department Reimbursement, 1979-1981 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Grant Employment Conditions, 1980-01-14 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - JLARC Exposure Draft Federal Funds in Virginia, 1980-09-16 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Mission Statement, 1980-12-01 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - CEC Program Evaluation, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Extension Agent Personnel Classification, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Interpretation to Faculty and Staff, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Unit Chairman Responsibilities, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Program of Work Fiscal Year 1980, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Memoranda With State Agencies, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - JLARC Study of Responsibilities and Financial Resources of Local Governments in Virginia, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - JLARC Report "Consolidation of Office Space in Roanoke", 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - JLARC Board Member Survey, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - JLARC Review of Virginia Division of Volunteerism, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - JLARC Review of the Virginia Division of Volunteerism, 1993-09-01 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Local Coordinate Committees (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Program Director Positions (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Response to JLARC Recommendation (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Series VI. Virginia Association of Extension Secretaries, 1958-1993
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Secretarial Association, 1960-1971 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Portfolio Judging, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Extension Secretaries Assoc., 1970-1984 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Organizational, Associations, Committees, etc., 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Committee Statewide Ext. Secretarial Assoc., 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Secretarial Association (Ext.) Campus, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Announcements, 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Annual Retreat, 1992-04-15 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Scholarship, 1990-1995 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1990-1995 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Minutes And Exec. Communication, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Series VII. Lucy Is Still Here papers, 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Series VIII. Slides, 1980-1989
  - New 4-H Leader Orientation slides, 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Slides [Inflation?], 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 9)